silversurfers.net 2014-05-17

# Privacy Policy « Silversurfers

Silverhairs Limited, the company which owns the website [www.silversurfers.com](http://www.silversurfers.com/) ( **Site** ), is totally committed to protect any personal data you provide to us and to process your personal data in accordance with this Privacy Policy and applicable laws.

This policy (together with our [terms and Conditions](http://www.silversurfers.com/terms-and-conditions-of-use-for-silverhairs-com/ "Terms and Conditions") and any other documents referred to on it) sets out how we use and protect information that you give to us when you use the Site and also when giving us your data and information for emails.

For the purpose of the Data Protection Act 1998 (the **Act** ), the data controller is Silverhairs Limited, Albury Mill, Mill Lane, Chilworth Guildford, Surrey GU4 8RU

Our nominated representative for the purpose of the Act is Martin Lock.

**1 What we may collect on Silversurfers.com  
**

1.1 We may collect and process the following information about you:  
(a) information that you provide by filling in forms on our Site. This includes information provided at the time of registering to use our site, subscribing to our service, posting material or requesting further services. This information may include your email address and your address and postcode, your username and password, your Facebook name, Pinterest name and Twitter handle, your blog and/or forum name and details;  
(b) information for which we may ask you when you enter a competition or promotion sponsored by the Site, and when you report a problem with our Site;  
(c) if you contact us, we may keep a record of that correspondence;  
(d) we may also ask you to complete surveys that we use for research purposes, although you do not have to respond to them;  
(e) details of transactions you carry out through our site and of the fulfilment of your orders; and  
(f) details of your visits to our site including, but not limited to, traffic data, location data, weblogs and other communication data, whether this is required for our own billing purposes or otherwise and the resources that you access.  
(g) Credit & debit cards details. We do not store credit card details nor do we share customer details with any 3rd parties.  
(h) Delivery Policy of Silversurfers discount card purchased via Silversurfers.com.  
Silversurfers Limited use Paypal to facilitate all credit and debit and Paypal payments to enable customers pay for the Silversurfers Discount Card. Customer register their details on Silversurfers.com and register for a Silversurfers Discount Card and make a £10 payment for it, which they will then receive within a period of 2 weeks.  
(i) Refund & cancellation policy.  
Silversurfers Limited offer a refund if customers are not satisfied with their card within 1 month of purchase. To apply for a refund please [contact us](http://www.silversurfers.com/contact/ "Contact Us").

1.2 We may collect information about your computer, including where available your IP address, operating system and browser type, for system administration and to report aggregate information to our advertisers. This is statistical data about our users’ browsing actions and patterns, and does not identify any individual.  
****

**2 How we use your information you have given us at www.silversurfers.com**  
2.1 We may use your information if you have registered with the Site and its blogs, forums, and if you request access to our Facebook, Pinterest, and Twitter accounts. If you have registered your email address we will use this to send you our email newsletters which contain information, competitions, adverts and links to other websites.  
2.2 If you enter your details in a competition or a promotion we may ask for details of your address or phone number or email so that we can contact you and send you details of the competition or promotion or if we need to notify any winners.  
2.3 We also use information held about you in the following ways:

(a) to ensure that content from our site is presented in the most effective manner for you and for your computer;  
(b) to provide you with information, products or services that you request from us or which we feel may interest you, where you have consented to be contacted for such purposes;  
(c) to carry out our obligations arising from any contracts entered into between you and us;  
(d) to allow you to participate in interactive features of our service, when you choose to do so; and  
(e) to notify you about changes to our service.

2.4 We may also use your data, or permit selected third parties to use your data, to provide you with information about goods and services which may be of interest to you and we or they may contact you about these by post, telephone or email.

2.5 If you are an existing customer, we will only contact you by electronic means (e-mail or SMS) with information about goods and services similar to those which were the subject of a previous sale to you.

2.6 If you are a new customer, and where we permit selected third parties to use your data, we (or they) will contact you by electronic means only if you have consented to this.

2.7 If you do not want us to use your data in this way, or to pass your details on to third parties for marketing purposes, please tick the relevant box situated on the registration form on which we collect your data.

2.8 [We do not disclose information about identifiable individuals to our advertisers, but we may provide them with aggregate information about our users (for example, we may inform them that 500 men aged over 50 have clicked on their advertisement on any given day). We may also use such aggregate information to help advertisers reach the kind of audience they want to target (for example, women in London SW1). We may make use of the personal data we have collected from you to enable us to comply with our advertisers' wishes by displaying their advertisement to that target audience.]  
****

**3 Where we store your personal data**

3.1 The data that we collect from you may be transferred to, and stored at, a destination outside the European Economic Area ( **EEA** ). It may also be processed by staff operating outside the EEA who work for us or for one of our suppliers. Such staff maybe engaged in, among other things, the fulfilment of your order, the processing of your payment details and the provision of support services. By submitting your personal data, you agree to this transfer, storing or processing.  We will take all steps reasonably necessary to ensure that your data is treated securely and in accordance with this privacy policy.  
****

**4 Cookies and analytics**

4.1 The Site, in common with most websites, has cookies which enable a much easier experience for our users and also allow us to improve our site.. Cookies are simply “text files” which contain just two pieces of information which a website name and a unique user ID (a user ID is the same as a username. It’s just a sequence of characters and numbers that is used when you log into a computer or onto the Internet and is used for identification). Our website uses cookies to distinguish you from other users of our website. For detailed information on the cookies we use and the purposes for which we use them see our [Cookie policy](http://www.silversurfers.com/cookie-policy/ "Cookie Policy").

4.2 Cookies work by being downloaded onto your Personal Computer (PC) the first time you visit a website. Then the next time you visit that website your PC just checks to see if it has a Cookie that is relevant to that site and send the information contained in the Cookie back to the website. All this takes milliseconds. The website then “checks” that you have been on it before by the use of the Cookie check and with this then varies the content which is presented to you on the website according to what you have used the previous time or even multiple times.

4.3 Some Cookies are much more sophisticated for example they can record how long you stay on certain pages and what you click on in those pages and even your preferences for page layouts, and which banner adverts you prefer so that different adverts can be shown to you. The benefits of Cookies are many; they really make your interaction with websites much easier so for example, they remember details when you are shopping online making this experience much easier

4.4 We also use Google analytics on our Site which measure how many users and customers we have on the website and which pages they visit. We use this information to understand how our Site is performing and many large websites use similar analytics from companies like Google.  
****

**5 Banners, links and contacts to other websites**

When using our Site you may go through to other websites, blogs, forums, adverts, competition and offers. When doing this, this Site’s privacy policy does not apply and the privacy policy and terms and conditions of that website, blog, forum, advert, competition apply. We take no responsibility or liability for any information, cookies or information collected by these other sites.  Please check these policies before you submit any personal data to these sites.

**6 Security**

6.1 We are dedicated to maintain the security of all its data and to prevent unauthorized access through the implementation of appropriate technical measures, as far as is reasonably possible. Such security measures also include access restrictions, i.e. that data may be accessed only by a limited number of persons within Silversurfers.com

6.2 All information you provide to us is stored on our secure servers. Where we have given you (or where you have chosen) a password which enables you to access certain parts of our site, you are responsible for keeping this password confidential. We ask you not to share a password with anyone.

6.3 Unfortunately, the transmission of information via the internet is not completely secure. Although we will do our best to protect your personal data, we cannot guarantee the security of your data transmitted to our site; any transmission is at your own risk. Once we have received your information, we will use strict procedures and security features to try to prevent unauthorised access.  
****

**7 Disclosure of your information**

7.1 We may disclose your personal information to third parties:

(a) in the event that we sell or buy any business or assets, in which case we may disclose your personal data to the prospective seller or buyer of such business or assets;  
(b) if Silverhairs Limited or substantially all of its assets are acquired by a third party, in which case personal data held by it about its customers will be one of the transferred assets;  
(c) if we are under a duty to disclose or share your personal data in order to comply with any legal obligation, or in order to enforce or apply our [terms of use](http://www.silversurfers.com/acceptable-use-policy/ "Acceptable Use Policy") and other agreements; or to protect the rights, property, or safety of Silverhairs Limited, our customers, or others. This includes exchanging information with other companies and organisations for the purposes of fraud protection and credit risk reduction.  
****

**8 Your rights**

You have the right to ask us not to process your personal data for marketing purposes. We will usually inform you (before collecting your data) if we intend to use your data for such purposes or if we intend to disclose your information to any third party for such purposes. You can exercise your right to prevent such processing by checking certain boxes on the forms we use to collect your data.  You can also exercise the right at any time by [contacting us ](http://www.silversurfers.com/contact/)

**9 Access to information**

The Act gives you the right to access information held about you. Your right of access can be exercised in accordance with the Act. Any access request may be subject to a fee of £10 to meet our costs in providing you with details of the information we hold about you.

**10 Changes to our privacy policy**

Any changes we may make to our privacy policy in the future will be posted on this page and, where appropriate, notified to you by e-mail.

**11 Contact**

Questions, comments and requests regarding this privacy policy are welcomed and should be addressed [here](http://www.silversurfers.com/contact/ "Contact us")
